good it all right I managed I managed to
do it
figure out how to go alive from the
having read preach all that went live
several times but not from pre schedules
on that yours are not greatest I'm sick
I was like this morning but I have this
one so I I love how the universe is like
or are you really committed cuz here's a
cold here is I'm exhausted from the
weekend and your kids home you can find
your car get started again look at
school buzz so I'm here let me see if I
can figure out how do we buy people cuz
this is my first time participants pop
up called time stands one of this is
just a fail in the right direction or
allow failure in the right direction
it's not to fail in stream yep donut in
the street microphone let's see here
actually have an option to invite people
and on you on Facebook at those maybe
this won't work and we'll start doing
Facebook live ones instead okay I'm here
here for an hour like minute to do so
how do we retire capitalism it's a bit
like it's like dismantle destroy call it
retirement that's a positive way I'm
saying like we're done go on thanks for
everything you've done
now go on and do now we need something
new and so I made some notes because
when you know especially my current
state it's not quite gonna work so gonna
grab my tea here though I'm sick today
honestly and I'm in my pajamas that's
maybe a little more than I usually
here's they generally not in my pajamas
but my well be doing these for my bed
because that's what I'm doing it's where
I can record on my house it's where I
spend most of my time
it's what I'm doing so how do we
hey there's a be more hello how do we
retire
capitalism is through technology
he liked it so much better when I was
rehearsing it by myself the video but I
wasn't sick then so her brains work you
doesn't it
so yes retiring technology I have
created a website called together tech
with Wix that explains a bit about what
I tried to put it in the comment section
or another comments the description
because I already down the description
it wouldn't let me edit because I hadn't
gone live yet so anyway I'm the
beautiful irony that my technical
literacy isn't up where I would like it
to be and yet I am starting the mother
of all tech startups to save the world
but that's the point I don't need to be
all those things we no longer need
everyone to be everything in the world
we need people to be who they are and
have the tools in place to collaborate
with other people who can make up where
they lack and that's what I will be
doing we will be doing when it becomes
week more we less I so I have an outline
here I do it's like oh yeah I have to
actually start the starting point
alright so we creating the ideas in our
regular everyday society we have
infrastructure that we all use we have
roads we have hospitals and schools and
things that we don't need to have
created our ourselves in order to use
infrastructure it's called him structure
and I'm looking to create the online
infrastructure for a brand new system
and so instead of me or a corporation
creating it and in which case we comp
against everything that every other
corporation and individual comes up
against witches marketing issues and
financial issues and credibility issues
and then I even if you're successful and
create a project it's an isolation and
then everything else is in competition
with it or if it is working together
then someone's paying someone and
there's inefficiency there so creating a
Tec system a bunch of apps that work
together to improve our our world why
technology alleged yes technology to me
is an amazing tool it gives us the
ability to do this in a way that
wouldn't have been possible two decades
ago or even probably a decade ago and is
only now starting to be it's only now
starting that like people enough people
are waking up to the fact that we're
world is maybe not doing so great but
there's enough technology to be able to
create the ways to collaborate as well
so return so anyway the reason
technology is I see technology having
three main solutions for us one is
knowledge so everything you want to know
about is online it's just not organized
nor do we know if we can trust it and so
even this idea that under like when you
watch a documentary they're like but do
your own research it's like okay so
we're all supposed to not only like I
can't trust that you're telling me the
information I have to go do my own
research and even if I do and it proves
you right or wrong I then have to tell
the person I'm talking to you to go do
their own research right they're like
well I did the research it show this so
there's that trust component that we
need and it's just not accessible for
everyone to research everything right
there's enough hours in the day we have
to be able to trust somewhere but
understandably we don't trust and
shouldn't trust what's already out there
right how do you know it's credible how
do you know just that how do you know
it's credible how do you know it's real
and trustworthy and for me the only way
I'm gonna be able to trust it is if I'm
involved in the creation of it if I can
see transparently where that information
came from how could that information is
and what we can do with that information
and for me I wanted to be able to I want
to be able to understand it my brain
understand it so we want information
that is trustworthy and accessible to
all different learning types and with
the crowd we can do that we already
aren't I mean that I mean Wikipedia does
that in a large way but it's also not
transparent and it's not democratic so
if you come up with something that uses
Wikipedia's information you don't have
permission to use that right I'd like to
make a for profit or your own not for
profit but they're not for profit like
you have to go through all of the steps
to getting permission to do that
it is to make knowledge base that we can
all trust and all use because we've
decided what that means right like what
makes science trustworthy what is and
then we're voting on the algorithm that
makes a trustworthy we're not voting on
whether this one piece of science is
good or bad that makes sense one of the
other things technology does is connects
us Facebook good bad ugly makes it so
that I have at least surface level
interactions with people that I don't
see on a daily basis that like my high
school friends or high school
acquaintances my extended family the
'train has connected us in ways that we
were never able to before and that my
parents can watch my kid grow up and
actually feel even though they're not in
the same city can actually feel a real
connection with her and she feels a real
connection with them because they're
able to watch it watched video to you
their hope to do that over Skype right
so the other thing it does kind of with
knowledge and connection is this like
tools and systems that are created like
apps and systems that we never really
had in place before like Airbnb or uber
which they don't create their own like
they didn't create a hotel they created
a system that allows people to rent out
a room they didn't create their fleet of
vehicles they created a system that
helped people drivers be able to offer
rides to people with their own vehicle
that's a system a service that they
created and it's a for-profit system
that they created but the truth is
overnight a collective could start their
own mover and own their own Airbnb and
take over it's the only way to take
those over because they do have a place
in that a big place in the market so if
we're able to create our own system that
has knowledge we can trust helps us get
connected to people whether one single
partner in relationship whether business
partners
in a group are spiritual communities or
our hobby communities that we can easily
find people to connect with because when
you give people connection and a sense
of purpose in place a lot of the
horrible evils in this world disappear a
lot of them exist because people feel
isolated and lonely and disconnected and
misunderstood and so yeah so although in
my vision
we eventually like only means of
production and there's this parallel
system that competes with and if done
right I then we out-compete competition
together because cooperation is more
powerful than competition
it's just how it works like if you have
one person in a hundred in a discipline
that's willing to cooperate and share
that knowledge with everyone else they
Trump the 99 that aren't right like
those 99 they're in competition and like
no I don't want to I'll put me out of a
job well you just need one if you're
hundred to put that information out
there and yeah maybe if that was your
only job was to be a gatekeeper to
knowledge sorry that's no longer a
needed profession be able to use that
knowledge and in a better way with
someone is definitely needed so the idea
of owning it together that's why it's
called together tech because we're doing
it together we're gonna create it
together we're gonna run it together
we're gonna fund it together and we're
gonna own it together that system is
already in place in some ways in the
corporate structure called a cooperative
where cooperatives are owned by a group
generally workers or consumers but
there's also producer cooperatives the
thing I'm envisioning is very much a
consumer cooperative so like MEK which
is not gonna call up in Canada and you
have to be a member
cause five dollars then you get about in
the court of directors and five dollars
total is what it costs to be a member if
neck or credit unions which have
membership so they're they're a bank
that's run not-for-profit if you don't
know that get on board to a credit union
they might not be able to offer the same
because they're not allowed to be as big
and they don't have the same rule is
there any was necessarily able to offer
the same rates so a lot of people
understandably are going to go to a
Bank but ethically credit unions are
where we want them or funds to be
because they are democratic they aren't
necessarily transparent but it's one
member one vote and there's transparent
as they can be with the technology like
I don't think that they're signs and all
transparent like a bank but they had to
ever compete with banks so in the same
way they have to be anyway sidetracked
so yeah together we're gonna fund it
together we're gonna own it together
we're gonna run it now that's not
possible
current leaks we don't have the
technology to do that so we need to one
of our first projects needs to be to
create the technology to collaborate
online like that's the infrastructure
we're creating and we're giving people
access to knowledge connection and tools
with so not explain it as well that's
right that's why this is week one this
is faylene week one and I'm gonna keep
explaining this until there's enough
people on board to understand it it's
also I have the website because the
website explains a better chunk of like
what it is we're trying to create and
this is supposed to be more FAQ more
like oh did you think about this and be
answering the questions and then it's
going to become once there's enough
people and interaction and enough then
we can break down the tasks to get to
the next stage which is the crowdfunding
stage of funding our first project and
what we need people on board first the
whole idea is to create things together
when it makes sense to create them it
doesn't make sense for me to spend my
time and energy and money creating
something that no one's gonna be
interested in so if no one's interested
in creating a cooperative together why
would I spend million dollars which I
totally have um creating that right if I
can if I can draw in and recruit enough
people that are like take my money we
need this yesterday that's what I know
it's feasible that's what I know the
message resonates with people enough but
there isn't that risk to it it isn't
about risky and a million dollars it's
about no ten thousand people a hundred
thousand people each put in twenty five
dollars now we have a million dollars to
co-create technology to collaborate and
creating that transparently
so that people know where their funds
are going to Besser ability because
again that technology doesn't exist yet
we're creating the technology in order
to be accountable to our members and
allow members to retain their boat and
not necessarily pass it on to the Board
of Directors but we're where we are so
that technology doesn't exist yet until
we create it we need to deal with what
we do have yes so I did those two points
the future
so the idea is 10 20 years in the future
after we have dozens or hundreds of
projects we live in a different world
then because when anyone can go online
and easily find connection easily have
information that they need to do what
they're put here to do that if they are
writing a historical novel it's super
easy because they have access to history
in a way that is visual or I think of
kinesthetic in a way it like that they
can see oh wait I person 1800s have a
stopwatch and stopwatches weren't
created yet like you can easily see that
because you can see the path I don't
know and I explained that exactly right
now but individuals have access to
systems so they're paying our membership
members are paying $10 per month and
getting access to apps tons and tons and
dozens of apps that work together in
concert to improve their lives that's
why they're choosing to do it later on
the early adopters will be wanting to
put money towards something or to create
this vision in the future later on you
don't need to see a vision of the future
it's just like like you don't need to
see Netflix vision to just be like
entertain me you don't need to see the
vision of hey when we're all working
together collaboratively we're all
better off because you're like no this
apps help me eat better is thats helping
me save way more than ten dollars a
month yes I'm only to pay ten dollars
worth of it it makes sense just like
that out for that and I get to vote and
be kept up to date on all the other
projects sure even better so so it's
individual
in the future we have access to all the
knowledge we need we have access to the
tools to mitigate where we fall short so
if we're not great at time management we
have the tools do time management to do
project management to find the people we
need to collaborate with because we're
not all great at finding the people or
running a group and that doesn't mean
we're not valuable contributing human
beings it just means we don't have the
perfect set of skills to get an idea out
there and ask those people it sucks like
it sucks that it's hard to get an idea
out there which is why I'm going through
this system to create an idea
I mean who I don't necessarily want to
be being more of an extrovert putting
myself online in order to create the
system so nobody else has to no one else
should have to get a platform in order
to create something that's gonna save us
all they should just be like hey do you
think this idea could save us all well
let's look into it here's the pros
here's the cons here's what how do we
take a step forward right those are
possibly dozens of people involved in
that process of like breaking it down
into components and that's what I'm
looking for I'm creating with what I'm
creating I'm creating what I would need
to create this well creating without
that if that makes any kind of sense so
it's like okay well if I could just go
on and be like hey who wants to start I
mean the global cooperative if it
already existed be like hey who wants to
start a food app like let's draw our
permaculture app that like plans out
your garden tells you when to water it
tells you when to harvest it works with
your neighbors so that you know like my
tomatoes are all right we have X like
sky's the limit we can create whatever
we want to create as we're funding it
and we're funding projects for purpose
and not for profit so where it makes
sense it doesn't make sense to spend 10
million dollars on an app that one
person's going to use but it does make
sense to spend a million dollars on an
app that a million people are gonna use
to coordinate and collaborate and create
great amazing basic stuff so yes oh I
have here the kind of approach so in the
future 10 20 years we have access to
history science is a big one because no
matter how rich you are like Steve Jobs
died of cancer
you cannot buy access to innovation that
we don't have yet and the secretive
profit driven innovation gets us
somewhere but it's not the best option
if we were open with our cancer research
if both like when I give money to cancer
research I got to see where that money
actually went and it was about like
having less cancer when you have cancer
surviving it and actually curing it and
I don't care if that makes profit that
gets us better research where you don't
have to wait a decade to hear about
something new because a scientist has to
come with the idea run the accept the
funding for the project run the
experiment and then publish and then you
get it it's like a 10-year process if
it's a you know six seven year study and
instead be able to collaborate from day
one you're able to troubleshoot the
experiment you're able to say hey I'm
working on this collaborating with other
people around the world that are working
on it getting access right away to
information people's ideas if you take
eco and profit out of it and instead
you're there to solve cancer not to be
the person who solves cancer there could
still be the parallel system of no no I
need my name to be on it I want it to be
called blah blah blah method once it's
it's comes into existence I'll be able
to create the drug it's gonna cure
cancer so I can make billions of dollars
okay but if you want to create the pill
to cook it the cures cancer because you
want cancer cured those people want to
collaborate those people want to come
together so giving people access that
aren't necessarily scientists and
doctors access to information about
cancer so anyone could become a
researcher anyone just if you're
interested enough and you happen to have
a brain that can figure that out like
there's high school students have taken
huge leap forwards in cancer of like oh
wait did we think of trying this to test
for cancer and did you maybe this could
cure it we want people thinking outside
the box people who weren't necessarily
trained and with all these barriers
before ever getting to to med school and
science right of like oh you don't have
this personality you don't have you
didn't get straight A's so therefore
you're not you
not able to be on board with this
research well what if that person is the
one with the cure and they just happened
tonight of a brain that works going
through university or works to get into
university might have thrived in
university and so when we take back
together when we take back our science
our politics and our economics taking
back our history is important because
it's like it is so colonizer centric
that it's very European very male and
very people in power right you know we
don't necessarily learn about what like
the life was like for the everyday
people we can have access to that we can
find our collective like how we are all
relative related in a way that we don't
have access to before where it is very
us in them because we don't see the big
picture that we're all really a family
and I've got many generations back he
said I am you for all you know we have a
common ancestor there so when we have
access to especially the first three the
science economics and politics we shift
the globe we have access to politic all
information both like who who this
politician actually is not a spin from
the media but like who are they what
have they done in the past what are they
voted for who says they've committed
sexual assault you know like the bare
basics these days when the power isn't
in the hands of the media we've decided
what we want to know about politicians
and we've both Cooke collaborated we've
correlative
brought that together what is available
and what isn't available we've asked of
the politicians and if they don't want
to answer it well then you have that's
an answer you don't want to tell me what
your stance is on abortion that's the
answer that you won't tell me your
stance that's going to be if I'm
pro-life you're pro-choice and if you're
pro-choice or pro-life right it's like
no informations bad information so
taking back our politics means that our
politicians have to work in our best
interests because they're not going to
get our vote any other way we can create
political parties together they're
designed for that very process economics
is very based on competition right now
I'm very supply and demand
a lot of fails it's very
inefficient and a lot of its based on
spin and marking and of like oh we're a
green but totally promise for green look
we have a green label and everything and
we're healthier where no I want to know
the actual health I don't care that
you're telling me you're healthy you
have every reason to lie to me and spin
that I want to know is this one that
looks healthy healthy or less healthy
than this other one that's 50% of the
cost but this other one that's double
the price like what's the healthiest
what destroys the firm at the least what
has the least negative social impact or
the most positive social impact for
society and when we create those tools
who will have access to that knowledge
the system changes the other pieces like
that's the knowledge piece for
technology the connection piece if you
can be your authentic self which is
amazing look it feels amazing the one
piece that's not amazing is if you are
being authentic surrounded by people who
are pulling you down because they don't
it scares them it's really hard to be
that alone if being your true self
doesn't mean you're isolated because you
can find your new family if your family
kicks you out you can find your new
community if your community Oster
surprises you you can find a new partner
if your partner you break up like if
that process is fairly easy it isn't it
isn't this fear anxiety driven
understandably like I'm gonna have no
family what am I gonna do I'm gonna have
no one to look after me no one to care
for me
yeah that's scary no one that loves me
and knows me for but the more we can
give people that connection the tools to
no matter what their skill set is no
matter how unique they are there's
people who are gonna love you for you
exactly you so that your job is to
become more you our job is to find where
those yous go
I like this group of people and will
there be people that like are absolutely
unlovable I don't think so
I think everyone has people of it will
love them but no one is ever
cup of tea if you are you're such a
freakin flavorless cup of tea and like
it's just it's not it's good to be
authentic and unique to be able to
harness that power to be able to give
people yes if your turns out you're gay
and a fundamentalist Christian community
you can still find your people even if
you don't leave that community because
maybe your community's online right like
even if you need to stay there because
you're looking after your ailing mother
you can send everyone around you as
yelling slurs 'hey you and being you at
least can find an online community it's
like listen the world isn't like that we
love you for you
come come live with us when that's no
longer when you know like I need to live
there creating the connection the others
one is the tools and systems there's so
many people around the world that have
ideas are like hey maybe I could like
coordinate with my neighbors and that's
like so hard you have to have the
specific personality be able to do that
person and kick-start that that project
if it's so easy because other people
have kick-started in other cities and
you can just piggyback off of them and
say oh yeah I want to start that here
who wants to help me start that here we
don't have a tool library let's start it
to a library when it's easy to opt into
a system where it's not never gonna be
okay we're the central planned food
system and here's your box of produce
and here's what you have to eat and
here's what you have to wear and here's
what you it's hopefully the opposite of
that where it's people saying hey this
is how I want to eat this is what stops
me from eating well
I need like prepared easy food but I
don't have to think about it to live it
to my door that's healthy that's a big
ask if I'm asking to not do anything to
get that if I'm asking to opt into a
system where okay I trade 10 hours a
week or on or $100 or whatever it
happens to be is what we've decided and
it's not a billion people working
together so a billion people have to
decide to have the same food system it's
a billion people breaking off into
groups saying hey what food system works
for us oh let's both why food oh this is
awesome this is where this is where that
works this is where it doesn't work
we're wasting this as a recruiting the
tools become more efficient and too
create those systems together so that
when I want to work with my neighbors
it's easy to do so because my neighbors
are on a neighborhood Facebook where
it's like hey J like let's have a block
party let's have a Halloween party let's
have who wants to help coordinate that
well we need a space we need food we
need a time and it can actually easily
work through people through that it's
like okay it sends out the poll that's
like are you available like when are you
available it can even just like if you
click off that yes community members can
see my talent or not they can see my
exact calendar but like hey I know this
is going out to my community ID my
neighbors do you like algorithm knows
their calendar and it's finding the
point where most people are available
like that's not and if you really don't
want it to do that then you're not
included like you can opt out of
anything if you're not into and out of
anything and so there is no coercion and
there is no force everything is
voluntary but we create it in such like
why would if you're if you are tracking
your data for food so here's how much
you spent on it here's how much time you
spent prepping it shopping for it making
it here's how much food actually went to
waste that you never ever touched and
therefore maybe you shouldn't have
bought the more you have access to that
information the more you're going to be
able to make better decisions more
nutritious more financially stable the
more we then have that that system in
place I kind of was talking about three
different things though like if you're
spending $500 a month on food and 80
hours a month on food also and we're
offering you for $400 a month and you
know 10 hours of or I just give two
different for like $400 and 10 hours a
month you can have your food needs met
you get to deliver you know we slow the
delivery driving we split up the food
prep we spread it's like where are you
gonna spend your time where's your money
like why wouldn't you opt into that I'm
just kind of like your needs easy like
it's going to meet your needs you were
meeting before yourself more easily
that's what and so explain a little bit
your
dollars a month when you become a member
once that's it once that threshold is
met or makes sense to charge people ten
dollars a month and we're charging
people ten dollars a month that gives
you access to all of the tools and
systems the knowledge and the ability to
connect gives you access to the apps the
technology that we've created
it doesn't mean you get your food for
free that's opportunity to a system
right that's like okay if we create an
Airbnb you get to use Airbnb for free
you don't get an automatic room in
someone's house for free I hate like the
people get to decide who when they rent
it out for what they and like we might
decide on a cap together we might decide
that 50% of the money earned goes to the
community like those kind of things and
but you never have to rent out your room
even if it's 50% goes to the community
and 50% you keep you never happy Airbnb
exists go do it on there like it's we're
creating things democratically but it
doesn't mean you get access right like
if we owned a factory I always go the
kraits toothpaste you don't have to use
it you're invited to use it when you use
it and you pay for it hopefully we've
already done the threshold so we know
how many people like this flavor we know
how many tubes we need we know and we've
asked we'd like both like hey all these
people all these people got bought
toothpaste from you
we could start a factory now but you're
asking them would you buy this flavor
slash ingredients from us when it's the
cooperative we don't just assume it yes
it's like this is a threshold bet and
then you don't get the toothpaste for
free until we're in that system where
that's actually it's like okay so you're
trading maybe an hour of time per year
to get your toothpaste needs met well
okay we're offsetting that because like
I don't wanna spend an hour in
toothpaste bag during an hour and you
know eyeglass factory or whatever it
happens to be it's like okay those
things can be offset where I'm spending
40 hours a year in the factory of my
choosing that's local so that I get
access to all of these things right like
there can be efficiency there where it's
not just the one project it's like okay
well where do I enjoy spending my time
and where I might need it not as was the
conversation this weekend about I called
some was a part over it's like oh yeah
you do the food system but
I'm over I'm a musician I'm just gonna
play my music and have sex like that's
not helpful the community now if you're
musician we've act like you've offered
and we're like yes we want music so that
we're harvesting and we're cooking and
we want your music played live that's a
completely different story but you don't
just get to like have an art skill but
nobody nobody has a desire for and then
call that your your work and get fed
right like you need to not starve we all
need to not starve food needs to be
involved but it's not everyone has to
slog all day every day in the kitchens
and fields because we create technology
and innovation where we have technology
and innovation so that we can spend less
and less and less time doing those
things that we're still splitting it up
unless there happens to be an abundance
of people who that's their passion for
and they want to give it to everyone
else and like yeah you can you can be
musician have some sex and get food
delivered but I don't think that's the
case I think there's people who that's
absolutely passionate my passion for
growing food making food but there's
nothing like that like just cuz you're
rational making food isn't mean you and
there's your one in a hundred people
you're not gonna want to cook for 99
other people every day right you might
want to cook for 10 people every day or
you might want to cook once every 10
days or whatever it happens to be so
yeah that you were opting into systems
your payment doesn't cover that it
doesn't like it will give you access to
the information your and therefore your
information so like a health app that
helps you stay healthy if we create that
you're getting that for $10 a month you
have to pay extra to get that but if
part of that health app is that you have
to take this supplement that is a real
cost to that you're gonna have to pay
the real cost right and if we're able
together like it starts out let's say
everyone or this group of people really
there's a vitamin X and they really need
it and it's like okay so we're sharing
information as to where it's the
cheapest so we can all go out and buy it
individually well now that we know that
there's enough people locally that are
buying that we can bulk buy it so that
it's this much cheaper okay now there's
even more people buying it worldwide in
Oracle in our cooperative can we start a
corporation like sorry can we start a
factory can we make our own what does
that bring the
down to for us or bringing quality up or
whatever it happens to be so then we
have access to vitamin X which is
cheaper and easier than what you were
spending it by yourself but it's still
not free and where it becomes free is
when yet like there
don't you think everything we make needs
to be accessible to the floor to be
accessible to people who have zero money
even the $10 a month that I'm talking
about will be there'll be a way to
offset that because everyone needs so
it's like you either have time or money
and trading one for the other so it's
like okay maybe you don't do ten dollars
a month maybe instead you're doing 10
hours of or tens that's like a dollar an
hour
you're doing an hour of time or whatever
it happens to be or the offset and if we
have all people doing time and nobody
pain it's not gonna work everyone pain
and nobody doing time that'll work a
little better but then we're gonna have
to pay people to do the time which means
money's all being used up but it's not
being used at create the technology
creating our own little grant pool that
people can access through democracy you
have a million people paying $10 a month
into a pool ten million dollars and on
can't do the math yes there's gonna be
there's gonna be the overhead of like
the corporation itself the but like okay
so a million dollars I think we can run
that for a million dollars month we have
ten million dollars nine million dollars
to go towards projects to creating the
next one and the truth is that million
dollars will increase as our projects
increase right if we have thousand
different projects thousand different
it's not going to be a million dollars
per project per month because the whole
point is to be more efficient so like
there's one HR department one legal
before it's like a legal department says
we need four different countries but
like there's a efficient like you don't
have to everyone's are fully autonomous
by itself that there is a central one
that's helping you with a lot of the a
lot of it yeah that there is what was
that point about so yeah we've gotten
really sidetracked in it so the idea is
we OH
compete competition because in a
cooperative system when somebody invents
it everyone gets it and that doesn't
mean
oh you invented a table now you are
obligated to make that same table for
all million bucks
it means you made a table you're an
individual you get to choose if you
share that with us you get to choose if
you are gonna make them and then give
them away and who can give them away -
if you are giving them away you get to
choose if you're gonna give the plans to
people so everyone can make one if they
want to like you get to choose the level
but generally speaking when you're a
cooperative person and you want people
to have access to what you created
there's a system to be able to do that
so it's not again ok now all the sudden
we have a factory of tables right it's
like no there's this blueprint that's
made oh you can't do you can't make a
table for a blueprint great there's a
Saturday course you can take to make
that exact table because 10 other people
have signed up and it's offered once a
year in your location because we need to
make sure there's the ten people to sign
up and it's held at our community I
don't say lab but that's wrong but what
working space but there's those type of
spaces so maybe again you might not get
access to that space for free or for
your ten dollars a month because we're
why why is it in Vancouver and on
Toronto or New York or say Bangladeshis
that's a country though isn't it yeah
Calcutta yeah like it's why isn't it in
like why does he get to be here instead
of there that can be the case that we
can say okay if you have a million
people sign up you get into a library if
you get like it's not you don't have to
fund it yourselves you know like we will
fund it for you if you have this many
people sign up right there's thresholds
that are met but also you don't have to
make that threshold if you can get a
thousand dedicated people together and
you're like we can do this with a
thousand people it's made easier for you
still you've had all the other people
all the other cities who done it who've
made it easier and worn the path for you
so it's easier for you to do it the idea
basically I don't miss it tooks when he
make sounds just perfect I'm sick today
I'm gonna do another I'm doing this
every week until there's there's enough
out of people
so that we're creating the scaffolding
under our existing world our existing
world is working its destroying us
destroying our planet causing war and
causing but like we're alive we have
food most of us have food in the markets
or access to food somewhere we're not
starving to death except those of us
that are that we don't annihilate the
whole system to 0 and then Creek
co-create together because that is chaos
that is violence if you all of a sudden
overtook our government and I was in
power I don't know how to get food item
what if they stop working like I don't I
don't not actually get the food to the
market I don't know how the system runs
I don't think they know how the system
runs but what we need is to be able have
access to that information so we're
we're we have all the systems in place
that online tools exist we're gonna have
to co-create a lot of them off the bat
because they're too inaccessible they're
too expensive they don't work in
collaboration with other things but we
can use them as far as we can I use
Google Docs for a lot of like Google
Drive sorry for a lot of things I use
Facebook for a lot of things and
whatever tools in front of me until we
can co-create something as good or
better available to everyone we need to
use what's out there and so and we do
that with everything it's like okay I'm
not and now I'm only gonna go we're
gonna create our own medical system I'm
only gonna go to that and only use our
pharmaceuticals it's like no drugs exist
pharmaceuticals exist very imperfectly I
would really like to have access to that
information but we don't have to
co-create that from day one we can have
conversations about how to make our
health care system better when you
create apps to code to track our health
and kind of create our own healthcare
system or at least a base level like if
you don't have access to a doctor we
have access to this app it's better than
nothing yes we're creating the
scaffolding underneath because
collapsing what we currently have
without something to replace it is
violent and chaotic and I would like not
violence and chaos so I think most
people would like not buy one seek a us
and no point are we going in and
violently taking over anything we're not
even like really legally taking over
things we are asking for collaboration
voluntary hours voluntary contribution
would be like kind of if your government
was like do you want to pay taxes here's
where they're gonna go to you pick where
you don't want to pay them it's like no
war
Thanks no all right yes to schools even
if my I don't have a kid because that's
probably important it's like okay well
we get to create the scaffolding
underneath with tech because it's gonna
be the most bang for our buck and as we
collect data on through tech as we
collect the data on where it makes sense
when thresholds are met we then go off
of tacking create by farms and lands and
things that make sense
in fact land might be one if sidetracked
for our first Carib funding campaign
goes really well instead of renting a
house which is what I'm envisioning for
our tech cooperative of tech people who
are gonna create together and have their
needs met so they can focus on that
instead of creating like in renting a
house for thousands of dollars month and
said we buy land and develop it so that
it's like its own city its own little
like mini city where we have our working
space we have living quarters we have
food we like it's all there and people
can come and visit and come and be a hub
of creating this it's like how big that
can be do this depending on how much we
carve fun right if we crowdfunding
million dollars we're not doing that cuz
it's not enough to buy lands and create
it if we crowd fun if we this thing
blows up and all its like 25 million
it's like yeah we could spend 5 million
of that creating a village creating
something buying an old town doing
something where it's like this is gonna
be your hub come and visit come and do
and this will be um it depends but it's
not it's like we need the 25 million to
make this go it's like no what we need
is 250,000 that's our you know that we
know cuz it's not you actually don't
need 150 thousand to create this
you might be able to create it for a
hundred thousand 50 thousand especially
with people offsetting it with free with
free labor because they're like yes I
want this to exist in the world but
that's the threshold of like oh that
means we've had a hundred or that means
we've had a thousand people donating $25
right investing $25 in this vision of
the future that is what we want we want
that hundred thousand people we want to
have we want the threshold of people
saying yes this needs to exist in the
world more than we want the money itself
but whatever that is that we get there's
going to be different things available
so also because we don't have the
technology yet in place 250,000 means
maybe that we have a dedicated team that
not me because clearly I saw that
clearly this is just a live video I
don't edit videos you see the other ones
on my channel they're just you take you
pretty much live ones because I don't
like I don't want to in it start with it
my brains power to figure out what
should be and shouldn't be in there and
it takes too much for me so I don't do
it and that's fine because my passion
isn't to make videos my passion is to
create this in the world if this already
existed I would be spending my days
waking up when I thought of a tech
project would be like whoa who wants to
make this with me and even less like
maybe I that's all I want to do is
create like this spark of an idea and
pass it off to other people if there's
other people to pass it off to because
other people that's they're like oh I
know how to do tag but I don't have the
idea I don't have you know like be who
you are
create what you want to create in the
way you want to create it those tools
are in place to do that we unlock so
much human potential in that way that we
don't even know what the world could
look like like if everyone's empowered
to be their best self medicine you're
her best self every day just like
working towards more patients and more
understanding and more but you are where
you are and yeah so try to explain
everything we're talking to myself for
an hour live video with no one having
been present but hey it's also awesome
so creating the scaffolding running a
parallel system beside the current
capitalist one so that there are two
systems and if the idea is this one is
voluntary and as people opt-in it gives
us more and more power more and more
money to grow more and more things to do
and you can be part of both on paying
taxes in this one because it's legal
right like it's like you have to be part
of both but eventually if this one does
what it's supposed to do and outcompetes
the competition version the competition
can't really exist when there's only 1%
of the people doing it there's only 1%
of the people who are living in
capitalism capitalism doesn't make sense
capitalism is exploitive especially when
you offer the people who are being
exploited another alternative it's like
okay
the rich people cannot like if this
doesn't entice rich I don't I think it
does I think there's tons of people out
there like just because you're rich
doesn't mean you're happy it doesn't
mean you have a cure for cancer for your
loved ones like there's so much to be
offered here I can get you have got to
get over that there will be a little bit
you have to give up a little bit it's
like okay maybe there's a point we're
like we don't want people who have 20
properties that they're not even using
enough rent you know we're not doing
anything you're not allowed to be here
unless you but I don't think I don't
think that's where we start at all I
think we start with it's like oh you
have 20 properties any chance you gonna
rent those out for less than cost us
like to the members like we invite
people ask them what what is it that you
want to do what how do you want to
contribute and then creating the tools
to be able to do that for everyone not
just for me not just because my brain
works this way and I want to be able to
create the tools that help me get my
health in check but help me get my
finances I want to work with other
people who are also maybe not the
greatest in those areas to create an app
that works for a hundred different
people its finances are horrible right
the hundred different people who have
chronic health problems like because it
works for those hunter it'll probably
work for the million yeah it's it's
being efficient because we're not having
to recreate everything every time you
don't to figure out the funding for your
project because the funding here already
exists you'd have to convince the
funders which is kind of the current
system but in a way that's open and
democratic where it's like okay if you
can't
Vincente of people that your app is
worthy of funds then it's not worthy of
the funds like it's like okay if they
aren't getting enough people to you if
it costs a hundred million dollars to
make it and there's a dozen people who
want to use it that's not a that's not
there may be times where that makes
sense for us to do because it's a life
saving for those twelve people maybe we
do it then as a group and we say yes
those people's life it's worth that but
we don't do that just cuz hey I won I
don't know to go fishing and this exact
apps very very particular and no one
else can use it except these 12 people
Oh get it if you're taking a fishing app
and there's all the fishermen out there
for sure people who am like yeah I want
that that's awesome that sounds great
the thresholds already there they're
already giving you their vote then yeah
they get to you and that gets created so
the funding doesn't have to be thought
of every time you don't have to with
funding very intimately tied is the
threshold of usability if you need
there's so many great projects out there
but they don't have enough people
knowing about them in order to make the
threshold to make it usable like um
Craigslist is an amazing website
especially for when it was created it
gives people knowledgeable more
knowledge more connection it does
connection and a system tool more so the
knowledge but having access to that
alright point what that was so yeah
we're creating the scaffolding values
down there I feel like room of the first
things the idea is any the values that
need to be in place in order to have a
global cooperative and have it function
are okay needs to be democratic which is
what any cooperatives gonna be it's
gonna be one number one vote you
generally vote for the board of
directors the board of directors can
fire and hire CEO it's how corporation
works we are going to not only
democratically vote for a board but be
able to transfer our delegation between
those eventually able to hold on to your
vote and vote on absolutely anything
that you care about but the technology
doesn't exist for that yet so right now
you're gonna have to be and just even
is to be able to vote for your board of
directors we have to creative beta for
that like something that's super easy
for it's like my bow goes to this Board
of Directors Board of Directors goes and
knows that as a board of director member
as a director on the board I have a
thousand votes so when I vote it's a
it's a thousand someone else on the
board is five thousand someone else has
ten right like it's not one number one
vote on the board because each chord
member has a different number of
Delegates under them people who
definitely give it a book to them a
member in good standing and so democracy
is an important piece of this
transparency in order to be democratic
in order to be able to expect people to
vote on issues whether themselves are
delegating it to someone else that
delegate that board director is still
gonna have to okay their decisions to
their members are still gonna have to be
like well the reason I voted this way in
order to be able to do that they need
access to information so the idea is
there is no hierarchy of information
everything that's available to the CEO
is available to every member all
information because that gives us so
much power and protection you can't have
someone come and talk to the CEO and say
oh we actually are just gonna amalgamate
all all of your information from your
members you have to give that to us
because there is no it's like cool I
have to put that to a vote or even if
it's not up for vote because it's a
legal matter I have to tell my members
just like I would have to tell my board
the membership is our board right like
we have an actual board it functions as
a board to move things forward but
transparency and information the only
way we're not transparent information is
where we join the technology yet and
where it doesn't make sense to do so in
which case we're transparent about not
being transparent okay this is security
matter we voted on it this group of
people is our security team they have
access to that information but other
people do not diversity diversity is a
very important point because it's the
fuel that drives everything it's what
makes this function is that we aren't
all the same we all have different
interests we all have different things
when we want to geek out we have
different skills to give we have
different limitations and so creating a
system that harnesses that diversity
instead of just like giving it false
like okay well we have this many of this
gender and this funny of this gender
this is like okay I don't like can a
person show up and whatever gender
expression they have and find their
place including people who are very like
this female feminine and cisnet men
masculine like people who are the the
old wait like the over time the one
we've always known those people get to
exist too you don't have to be like you
know gender-fluid hillary to be part it
becomes the diversity is what we tap
into and it's true diversity it's like
okay if all of your boxes make you who
you are we need room for all of your
boxes your race your gender your age
you're all of it without the ageism
racism and everything associated with it
but there's gonna be people who are
those things because they exist in the
world we need to make room for the
people that exist without the behavior
that we just like there's ways to do
that cooperation is a big value it's
like the whole thing the whole thing's
based on but the beauty is because we're
starting where we're starting the early
adopters are gonna be our co-operators
they're gonna be people who are putting
their money where their mouth is saying
and being like yes take my money so we
can create this together even if they
never put another hour into it it's like
that's enough putting the $10 a month
into it say are the $25 per project in
the beginning is being the uber
cooperator it's saying yes I see the
vision I want to cooperate
I wanted platform I can call I can
cooperate with people on cooperation is
a big value one of the other values
which is not the top four or like
fundamental we cannot do this without it
the fifth one is a little more Wiggly a
little more like okay this wasn't that
then I guess I'd still be a part but it
makes it so much easier better faster to
get everything done which is we need it
to be fun and easy if it's gonna be hard
and a slog every time I come on if I
have to like watch every word I say
because I'm going to offend everyone and
like it's zero humor because humor is
always offensive to someone people
aren't gonna want to come and be a part
of it and it doesn't mean like it's it's
having room for everything so it's like
okay if my sense of humor offends you
how do we
you safe and me able to help because
it's like humor is a tool it's a defense
mechanism it's all like it's everything
it helps people football bit helps like
what I find some humor and some for sure
and I turn off those comedians and I
don't watch them and it's like okay we
need to be able to why is one person's
triggers trumping other person's
triggers there are certain ones that are
pretty universal people who like half
the population with the muties movement
is pretty much experience sexual assault
so maybe I put a trigger warning about
sexual assault stuff right children
being hurt or injured or sick like
certain things or like yes those are
huge
maybe we need your news but other things
it's like okay well I get offended when
people use the word their word owner to
mean a deadbeat dad though they're like
oh he's just a donor like no my
daughter's a donor he's amazing and like
the best
he's like my favor I sing for people
because he gave me my kid like that
isn't difficult like so that's what I
need trigger warnings on well I'm that's
ridiculous and you can't have every
trigger warning for everything so you
need to have either a system that helps
people with their triggers I get their
triggers but everyone anyway it's a
whole other type regret poignant it
needs to be fun and easy which means we
have to be willing to let people make
mistakes we have to be willing to let
people show up who they and how they are
which means they're not gonna be all
woke all the time especially as well
because we are you know like that's why
it's called woke like you to waking up
process right just because you're a
feminist doesn't mean you're a trans
right activist it doesn't mean you don't
have racism says we're all transphobic
we're all sexist we're all because we
live in this world that our world is
that and to not account for that to not
say that that's just the truth of where
it is at the moment I don't know it's
it's hurting us more the easy bit is
just about allowing people to do what's
easy for them because other people will
do it's not easy for you like I just
went on a big camping trip with a
community and I get a lot of anxiety
driving on the highway so someone else
drove my car that wasn't a requirement
of her to do she enjoyed doing it I like
it it's that kind of thing I became it
was easy for me I said show up it was
easy for her she just had to drive right
like it was like okay me driving would
have been not easy her I don't know
we're finding another ride up there
might have not been easy she had access
to another vehicle but like making it
fun and easy gamifying it understanding
that was fun for one person isn't fun
for another what's easy for one person
isn't easy for another and working with
that creating the tools that makes that
work is a big value that I think is
important
well idea is we create a system that
harnesses cooperation overcome not even
over because competition exists it's our
air we breathe in the world create a
system for the co-operators we take over
from the competitors because cooperation
kicks competitions ass every time you
need you have everyone out there
competing over like who's gonna make the
best mug one person a cooperator 3d
prints a mug and puts that online you
know work it out competitions done and
as one person goes a little but I have
an even better mug rate someone else
just 3d print like just gave you that
now like it's like you the comp the
cooperation with technology outcompetes
competition because the competition is
it's is old I mean so it's cooperation
but like it's it's what we have and it
keeps innovation from happening in a lot
of ways and we're harnessing the the
cooperate editor I don't know exactly
I'd explain it but like we create for
purpose instead of profit and we
cooperate we naturally take over from
capitalism because capitalism can't
exist in it if you had 10 billion people
create a door-to-door delivery service
with our own goods and services that
like people made out of their houses and
bulk buying what's already available in
from from corporations and then delivery
them and we created that system and we
hundred million people opted into using
that system and it's better faster
cheaper then Amazon how the Sun Goes
Away we don't have to have a discussion
of whether they're paying their workers
well because they don't exist if we
don't give them our money and we can do
that with every single field we can do
that with every single industry like
competition doesn't work in corporations
involved because competition can't
compete with cooperation cooperation can
absolutely out-compete competition
and so yeah that's been kind of the gist
of it so what I'm going to be doing is
showing up here every Monday and doing
this for an hour right now while we work
through the phases whatever face we're
currently on is the one-on-one time on
right now is education recruitment so
showing up for one hour a week in how I
am how I'm able to communicate this
message I'm going to be keeping the
website up to date with kind of a big
picture of like what cuz clearly I'm
really great at explaining this in the
moment um you go to the website see that
for any new members ie all members
members new as people see that and
create and want to come on board they
attend the it's not mandatory you can
attend as many or as few of these of
these as you want I understand not
everyone is available at 10 a.m. Pacific
Standard Time on Mondays here in Pacific
Standard Time very few people are
because they're working but the good
thing about a global cooperatives we got
time zones and there's it's evening
somewhere it's consider the weekend
somewhere that is not true that it's not
how time zones work still today some
stuff for some people it's tomorrow but
that's about as far as we go that yeah
I'm gonna show up here I'm gonna keep
the website up to date I also have a
Facebook and Twitter account that I'm
gonna be sharing like random thoughts
that come to me throughout the the week
that are very tied to cooperation in my
own person and my own journey towards
being my more authentic self and and
bringing my gifts to the world and how I
can collaborate and contribute to the
world to make it a better place well
creating the system that everyone can do
that with so my personal but not
personally called Krabbe democracy
Twitter account at Facebook account
follow me there so that you can stay up
to date I will post the live video and I
figure out how to like invite people off
youtube I don't maybe we'll do periscope
so it can be up Twitter I don't know
there weren't any people today but I'm
gonna keep showing up and the idea is
there's gonna be no people and there'll
be some people that's gonna be an
awkward situation because I'm maybe not
beulah there'll be a lots of people once
we get more and more people where
there's like hundreds of
people showing up every Monday to be a
part of this then we can start breaking
down the project and saying this is
here's what action you see it done we
need a beta so we can vote for our board
of directors we need to do the video for
the crowdfunding campaign right like
what once we have actual someone can
break down the task someone else can
take on those tasks and this will become
our board meeting those will become our
they'll be people who are involved who
are like we're gonna all meet on camera
we'll all be part of the board people
won't be able to delegate their votes
because we're not the technology yet
once people can once any people have
money in the game so trolls can come on
until you get their vote
there is no how involved you are is your
vote at the moment I'm the most involved
person I have a hundred percent of the
votes moment which is just I'm gonna
show up on Mondays I vote yes to that
I'm gonna yes showing up on Monday
is Technium to Lebanon and moving this
forward the best of my ability until
there's more ability on board because I
can only do what's fun and easy and
there's big pieces of this that are not
easy for me so I'm doing them to the
best of my ability until someone else is
on board to do them to the best of their
ability which and so please join me if
you're have to sit anyone happens to
come across this please join me next
Monday 10:00 a.m. Pacific Standard Time
and let's retire capitalism